Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of New York City Miscellaneous Manuscripts, circa 1614-1933 (bulk 1641-1900) MS 443.19
New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society collection of New York City miscellaneous manuscripts
circa 1614-1933 (bulk 1641-1900)
New-York Historical Society
MS 443.19
3.8 Linear feet in 9 boxes
The collection was compiled over time by New-York Historical Society and is composed of miscellaneous documents related to New York City. Included are affidavits, correspondence, Common Council reports, muster rolls, receipts, licenses, wills, property surveys, account statements, and a variety of other items. The collection contains documents regarding the Five Indian Nations; correspondence from the Sons of Liberty; a directive from the 16th British regiment allowing each solider a "half a galloon" of beer per day; records of the New York Revolutionary Committee; an 1803 document listing deaths from yellow fever; a brief history of the New York Asylum for Lying in Women; a 1904 invitation to the opening of the subway and a ticket for one ride; and the last piece of ticker tape from the Stock Market crash on October 29, 1929.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection may be stored offsite. To arrange to consult it, please go to www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Accruals
The collection is open to additional accessions, though N-YHS has generally stopped adding documents to it. Recent accessions of the type formerly placed in miscellaneous manuscripts are more likely to now be cataloged individually as an American Historical Manuscripts Collection (AHMC) item.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was compiled by N-YHS from various sources over time.
Arrangement
The container list is presented in rough chronological order. This differs from how the physical folders are arranged, though they seem to follow an uneven chronology as well. For documents that are a later copy of a document, the chronology (and date presented in the finding aid) is based on the date of the copied document. Undated items are presented in the finding aid in the approximate chronology implied by their place in the physical sequence of folders.
Related Materials
One practical aspect of the miscellaneous manuscripts collection is that all of the items are of a size, though perhaps folded, that will fit in a standard document box. Larger miscellaneous manuscripts stored in flat file folders are in a separate collection; see the Oversize Manuscripts collection (MS OS), specifically Series I.
Scope and Contents
The collection was compiled over time by New-York Historical Society and is composed of miscellaneous documents related to New York City. Included are affidavits, correspondence, Common Council reports, muster rolls, receipts, licenses, wills, property surveys, account statements, and a variety of other items. Although the bulk of the collection consists of original documents, many are various forms of copies of originals.
The collection contains documents regarding the Five Indian Nations; correspondence from the Sons of Liberty; a directive from the 16th British regiment allowing each solider a "half a galloon" of beer per day; records of the New York Revolutionary Committee; an 1803 document listing deaths from yellow fever; a brief history of the New York Asylum for Lying in Women; a 1904 invitation to the opening of the subway and a ticket for one ride; and the last piece of ticker tape from the Stock Market crash on October 29, 1929.
New York (N.Y.) -- Commerce.; New York (N.Y.) -- History.; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government.; Affidavits.; Financial records.; Judicial records.; Letters (correspondence); Minutes (administrative records); Resolutions (administrative records); African Americans.; Indians Of North America -- New York (State); Justice, Administration of -- New York (State).; Real property -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Proposed Coat of Arms for New Amsterdam, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Extracts from Documents, 1614-1665 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  Handwritten notes regarding early history of New York
- Transcripts of 4 Dutch Documents, 1627-1650, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Documents found among the papers of Mrs. Clark G. Voorhees
- Receipt [Dutch] concerning Abraham Planck of Paulus Hook, New Netherland, and signed by Cornelius Van Tienhoven, Provincial Secretary, 1641 January (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Contracts RE: West Indian Company, 1646-1666 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from Governor Stuyvesant to John Winthrop, enclosing copy of letter to Governor Endecott, 1653 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Location of Lands in the City of New York of the Philipse Gouverneur Families, 1653-1834 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes a typed subject index (alphabetical); Table of Contents; Name Index (alphabetical).
- Order granting a petition of Augustyn Heerman, signed by Petrus Stuyvesant, Nicasius de Sille, and Pieter Tonneman, 1658 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photocopies of the original document located at the New York State Archives in New Netherland Council Dutch Colonial Council Minutes, box 7, volume 8, item 1078.
- Complaint by Gov. Stuyvesant to Gov. Berkeley (Va.) regarding the capture by Robert Downman of a "ship with negroes", 1660-1665, 1663 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Transcribed from the Records of the General Court of Virginia in 1847
- Translation of Journal kept by Dutch Commissioners on their voyage to Herfort, 1663 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Copy of Articles of Surrender of the Colony of NY From the Dutch to the English, 1664 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Copy of the Duke of York's Commission to Col. Richard Nicholls, 1664 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Copy (1798) of Governor Richard Nicholl's Letter to the Magistrates of Maidstone at East Hampton, 1664 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Extract of a letter from Gov. Nicholls to H.R.H. The Duke of York, regarding decision on Connecticut lands, 1665 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Will [Dutch] of Joost Van Oblinus, 1664 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes an English translation copied by clerk, 1666 May 31.
- D.S. by James, Duke of York, and Richard Nicholls, 1669 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Certificate of Denization from Gov. Lovelace to John DeForest, 1670 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Copy of Agreement between John LaMontayne & John Van Schoonderwarte, 1671 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Commission from Charles II to Andros, 1674 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Photostat for research purposes
- Thanksgiving Proclamation [Dutch] by N. Bayard, Secretary, to be celebrated on July 11, 1674, 1674 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Petition of Jarvis Marshall and John Smith, 1676 (?) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Order of Arrest of Thomas ? Commanded by Thomas Delavall, Mayor of City of New York, 1679 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Nomination of Constables, signed by S. Vander Veer, 1680 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Appointment of Lewis De Kayes as Ensign of a Foot Co. of Militia, 1680 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Appointment of the Mayor and Council of Magistrates for City of New York, 1681 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Denis Fisher's Obligation of Captain Thomas Young of New Jersey, 1681 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Finding Samuel Wilson indebted to Thomas Norton, signed by John Lawrence, Gulian Verplanck, G. Minville, 1682 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Testimony of several persons before the Magistrates about Capt. Bacher (?) stabbing M. Graham, 1682 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Thos. Coker's Account against the City of New York for making a bridge, 1682 August (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Opinion of Committee appointed by Common Council regarding petition of Jacobus Roosevelt and documents regarding Beekman's Slip and Swamp, 1683-1733 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Warrant to Wm Bogardus & Isaac Gravenrod, signed by Cornelius Steenwyck, Wm. Beekman, & John Lawrence, 1683 January (Box 1, Folder 32)
- D.S. by Gabriel Minneaville, Mayor of the City of New York, 1684 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Recognizance of Thomas Davis and Sworn Testimony of Noel Jans, both signed by Gabriel Mineaville, Mayor of the City of New York, 1684 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Recognizance for the Appearance of a Witness, Anna Popland, by G. Minville, Mayor of the City of New York, 1684 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Complaint of Thomas Wyman against Henry Harpon, 1685 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Thomas Smith's Court filing regarding seizure of Brigantine Edmund & Martha Rinhard Cattishal masts., 1685 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Court Judgment for Defendant James Walsh against David Moody in case of servant woman; Complaint in case, 1686 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Certificate of Allegiance of Johannes Kip, signed by N. Bayard, Mayor, 1687 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Complaint against Cornelius Rossing (?), 1687 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dutch Document signed by, among others, Thomas Lawens, Jacob Boelens, Thenis deKey, Jan VanGelder, 1687 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Complaint of Dirck Vanderburgh against Thomas Howarden, 1688 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Minutes of Common Council Meeting, 1689 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Undated Plat with notations regarding high water mark, King's Highway, Jackoff's Farm (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Survey made of Widow Playground by Adolph Peters & Peter King, 1689 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- New York Province Act, 1691 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Act for settling, quieting, and confirming unto the Citys, Towns, Manors, and Freeholders within the Province of New York, their several grants, patents and rights. True Copy of Act - 1813 September 18
- Acts of Assembly of New York, 1691 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Transcriptions of Acts of 1691 regarding Province of New York, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Acts include Act to Divide Province into Shires and Counties; Act to Settle Courts of Justice; Charter of Liberties and Privileges granted to Inhabitants of New York.
- Account of Pay Due to Company of Fusileers under George Bradshaw from 24th of Sept. 1691 to 20th of March 1692, 1691-1692 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Signed by Robert Livingston
- Copio Authentyck, 1692 April 7 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  The document is likely in Dutch; signed by Johannes Schenk and others; sealed
- Warrant for Hanah Dean to pay Joseph Duchamps, 1692 July (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Will of Lawrence Delledyck, witnessed by Richard Ingoldsby, 1692 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Military Commission of Peter Matthews, Signed by Benjamin Fletcher, 1692 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Deed for a "negro" woman and two children sold by Martha DeHart to Paulus Linhard, 1693 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Affadavits of John Stout & John Smart, signed by Mayor DePeyster, 1693 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Minutes of Meeting of Common Council held at Fort William, 1693/4 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Boundary between New York and New Jersey; Militia cheerful and ready to serve Majesty
- Complaint of Anthony Farmer & George Rarcarrick of NYC Against Geelije Van Clyffe, widow, to pay her liquor license, 1694 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Agreement relating to minister's salary, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  The agreement is probably written in Dutch; undated but circa 1694
- Bond of Interest - John Godfrey; money received from Jacob Mayle, 1695 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Order to repair Ft. Schenectady, signed by Gov. Benjamin Fletcher, 1695 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Abjuration Oath against the Church of Rome; Test Associations against the Conspiracy formed and carried by Papists, 1698 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Memorial of John Montagne, in behalf of several hundred land owners beginning in 1698 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  The document was communicated to NYHS by J.T.W. Atson in 1824
- Plea by Parenlis Parmyter, 1699 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Copy of Decision signed by Thomas Trevor, John Hawles & John Povey, 1699 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Act was directed at the process for Granting of Denization in the Plantations (America); Approval of Order that Letters of Denization be not granted by any of the Governors of His Majesty's Plantations
- Estimate of Charges for Articles sent to New York by the Commissioners of Trade & Plantations, 1699 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Act passed in Parliament sent to Governor of New York, regarding the prevention of fraud in the importation of tobacco in bulk, 1699 June (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Bill of Sale from Elizabeth Lloyd to Miles Forester, 1699 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- History of New York, divided by decades 1699-1735, author unknown, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Cornelius Quick v. Thomas Clark, 1700 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  "Involving payment for a negro man named Sambo"
- Account of Costs & Charges of Material Issued out of His Majesty's Stores at New York in America, 1700-1701 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Information regarding goods, signed by Ducio Hungerford, purveyor of His Majesty's Customs, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Plea of Derek VanDerHeyden regarding value of pistol, 1700 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Recognizance of Ezekiel Grazalior (?), signed by David Provoost, mayor of City of New York, 1700 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Freedom from Corporation of the City of New York granted to Thomas Evans, 1701 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Signed and sealed by the Mayor of New York
- Fragment of Warrant, signed by Isaac DeRiemer, Mayor, 1701 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Recognizance of John Richardson and Recognizance of Stephen Buckenhaven, both signed by Isaac DeRiemer, Mayor of the City of New York, 1701 March 24, 1701 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Recognizance of John Windower, signed by Thos. Noell, Mayor of the City of New York, 1701 december 3 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Land Grant Petition of Henry Lane & John Sprat, Addressed to Hon. Rip Van Dam, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Involves 3 parcels of land previously underwater
- Appointment of Justices of the Peace for New York; Declaration of debt in which John Burrows complains against Moses Longstaffe & Christina Veenvos, 1702 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Includes wooden seal of New York
- D.S. by May Bickley, Attorney General of the Province of New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Mayor's Court Rejoinder in the case of Van Dyke v. Coortoons by M. Bickley, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Petition of Gerard Beekman regarding land owned by city adjoining his property, 1703 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Warrant to pay Peter Schuyler, 1703 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Two muster rolls of March and April and May and June of 1704 by Captain Peter Matthews (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 1709 New York State Council's Prayer to the Governor; Commission of Thos. Evans as Gunner at Ft. Anne, signed by Gov. Ingoldsby; Instructions issued by Gov. Ingoldsby to fit out Expedition Against the French at Canada (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Expedition includes Pennsylvania, New Hampshirre and the Five Nations which will be paid in wampum.
- Deposition by William Gouan, signed by Ebenezer Wilson (Mayor of New York), 1710 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Deposition concerned Benjamin Quaken and a Quaker, John Steevens
- List of Fees of Offices in New York, 1710 October 19 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Transcription of April 1710 letter by James DuPre to lordship (Governor Hunter) regarding naval stores (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Accounting of moneys received and distributed by Gov. Robert Hunter (Prov. of New York), estimate of sums needful for completing the settlement of Palatins at New York, 1710-1711 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Recognizance of Moses Hoss, signed by J.V. Cortlandt, Mayor of New York, 1711 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Appointment of Justices for New York in the reign of Queen Anne, 1711 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Seal of New York attached
- Grand Jury indictment of John Riggs for murder of John Grifith, 1711 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Panel of Grand Jury for City and County of New York (List of 28 names), 1711 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Recognizance of Moses Hart to Appear before next Court of General Quarters session, signed Samuel Bayard, 1711 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Recognizance of Jacob Franks to Appear before next Court of General Quarters session, signed Samuel Bayard, 1711 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Recognizance of Moses Levy to Appear before next Court of General Quarters session, signed by Samuel Bayard, 1711 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Recognizance of Abraham DeLacona to Appear before next Court of General Quarters session, signed Samuel Bayard, 1711 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Recognizance of Abraham DeLacona to Appear before next Court of General Quarters session, signed by Samuel Bayard, 1711 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Report on Account of Late Church Warden, Mr. Calcutt, 1712 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Signed by Johannes Jansen, Anthony Lynch, Noa Carzalete
- Recognizance of fifty pounds to Queen by Andrios Maosschack (?), 1712 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Pledges that "his negro man slave called Drogo had be forth coming when required to answer for Murder or any other crime…"
- Writ by Three Justices of the Peace in the City and County of New York, includes panel of grand jurors, 1712 July 22 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Justices: William Smith, Samuel Bayard, Abraham Wendell
- Recognizance of Tryntie (?) Cowenhoven to Appear before next Court of General Quarters session in November, signed Samuel Bayard, 1712 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Writ by Five Justices of the Peace in the City and County of New York, 1712 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Justices: Caleb Heathcote, David Jamison, William Smith, Johannes Janson and Jacobus Kip
- Recognizance of Frans Cowenhoven, Abraham Mesier, and Johannis Cowenhoven to appear before next Court of General Quarters session in November of 1712, written & signed by Samuel Bayard, 1713 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Presentation of the Grand Jurors (Thomas Nixon, Tunis Tibout, Cornelius Post, Simon Bredsheda, and David Coningham) to Queen, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Mary Weekham presented to Queen on grounds of "keeping a disorderly house to the disturbance of the neighborhood, and entertaining Negros"; undated but circa 1712
- Deposition by Elizabeth Swift, wife of Henry Swift, vintner, regarding assault by Captain Daven, 1714 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Signed by John Johnson, mayor of New York City as well as Elizabeth Swift
- Panel of Grand Jurors that includes, among others, Daniel Cromlyne, David Lyel, Elias Boudienauk, Joseph Robinson, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Panel of Grand Jurors that includes, among others, John Crooke, Octave Counrade, Oliver Schuyler, Johannes Hardingbrooke, 1714 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Receipt for Evert Wendell by John Barberie, 1714 August 5 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Transcript of 1714 speech to General Assembly by Captain Mulford (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Topics discussed includes Birth-right privilege; mentions many boats, masters, and custom duties
- Certificate of Citizenship to Gerrit Roos, 1715 July 15 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Humble Petition of Richard Davis for Relief, to Mayor and City Council, 1715 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Recognizance of Jacob Leisler and Francina Staats, appeared before Abraham Wendell, 1715 April 22 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Appointment for Justices for New York in the Reign of George I, 1715 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Has seal
- Account book of Anthony Ham of the Docks & Cranes, 1715 November - 1716 November (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Oath that Timothy Bagley personally appeared and produced a Commission of Lieutenant for Foot granted to him by Queen, signed by John Johnston, Mayor of New York, 1716 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Call for new elections by Mayor John Johnston to Isaac DeKiemer, alderman of the Out Ward, 1716 October 15 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  New elections because Matthias Hoppre, Constable, and Nicholas Romyn, Collector, are incapable of executing offices because of great age
- Election of New Officers in East Ward and West Ward, signed by Hermanus Van Gelder and written by Philip Van Cortlandt, 1716 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Election of New Officers in East Ward, signed and written by Philip Van Cortlandt, 1716 September 26 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Peltry bill and Invoice for Lead of Stephen DeLancey, 1717 April 2; 1718 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Pelts include otters, raccoons, wolves, deer, minks
- Humble Memorial of several members of the House of Representatives for the Colony of New York to his excellency, John Montgomerie, Captain General and Governour in Chief of the province of New York, New Jersey and Territories thereon depending in America, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Review ordinance of April 21, 1729 and make necessary changes, signed by members of the House of Representatives
- Custom House fragment regarding Ship Betty, 1720 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Affidavit signed by Hannah Worley & Hannah Sutton concerning Sarah Carrell, 1720 July (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Affidavit states that Mrses. Worley and Sutton heard cry of murder by Elizabeth Carrell and they went into Elizabeth Carrell's house and found Margaret Waters and Mary Ascum beating Sarah Carrell, mother of Elizabeth Carrell.
- Account of Officer (D. Crovootz) for collecting duty on the tonnage of vessels and enslaved persons, 1720 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Election of Alderman, Assistant, Assessors, Collector, Constables of North Ward, signed by Jacobus Kip, John Mann, Eggert Bursen, 1720 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Letter to the Government of the Colony of Massachusetts Bay regarding meeting with the Indians of the Five Nations, signed by Isaac Bobin, Secretary of the province of New York, 1721 October 9 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Governor of New York met with the Indian Nations, Massachusetts Bay should not send for Indian Nations again unless absolutely necessary
- Receipt Book of the Fielding Family of New York, 1721-1756 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Recognizance of William Watson for the good behavior of Ruth Guck, signed by John Cruger, 1721 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Petition of Jan Van Eps to Governor Burnet of Colony of New York concerning Five Indian Nations, 1722 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  Noted on back "A Copy of a petition"
- Writ Execution for Fauces Adarcel (?), 1722 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- A Proclamation adjourning the General Assembly, signed by Governor William Burnet, 1722 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Election of Aldermen, Assistants, Assessors, Constables, Surveyors of Highways for Bowery and Harlem Divisions, signed by Edward Blagge, 1722 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Writ of Enquiry & Return in case of Ebenezer Willson v. Isaac deRiemer, signed by 12 members of Civil Inquest Jury and Sheriff William Dugdale, 1723 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Sworn statement that Elias Hughes gave to Lawrence Wessells all of his estate in America if he did not return, 1723 Decmber 7 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Report of Committee appointed by the Common Council of examination of the public accounts of the City Treasurer, Cornelius DePeyster, 1723 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Sworn statement that Mary and Richard Terry provided a true inventory of Gershom Terry, deceased, signed by Benjamin Young, 1725 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Sworn statement of John Dupry renouncing executorship of Last Will and Testament of Elias Chardavine, 1726 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Sworn statement of Isaac Hicks that last will and testament of Abraham Southard was last will., 1726 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Deposition of Katherine Howard, 1726 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Patience Ashfor, City Spinster, called Katherine Howard many abusive names
- Grand Jury statement concerning keeping hogs, signed by Abraham Sanford, foreman, 1726 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Proclamation to adjourn the general Assembly until first Tuesday of September next, signed by William Burnet, Captain General and Governor in Chief of the Provinces of New York..., 1727 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Majesty's subjects are to take notice and govern themselves accordingly
- Distribution by Anne and Stephen Deblois of Estate of Maragret Trogley, 1727 August 28 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Sworn statement of wife is then sworn to by husband. Isaac Bobin is witness to the statement